Patricia L. Forrester

658 Oakridge Drive | Rochester, NY 14617

585-748-1107 https://www.linkedin.com/in/pforrester/

palforrester@gmail.com https://webforrester.netlify.app/

<u>SUMMARY</u>

Detail focused and innovative, with experience in Product Management, Project Management, embedded and full-stack web development, and integration of hardware and software systems. Major strengths include customer focused product requirements, effective software development processes and team leadership skills, with emphasis on achieving measurable results.

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Software: C, C++, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, React, Redux, Angular v6,

Node.js, Python, Mocha/Chai, Jasmine, PostgreSQL, Mongo DB, REST APIs,

Google Drive API, Google Cloud App Engine, Google Compute Engine, RabbitMQ

Dev Tools: Perforce, Jira, Jenkins, Trello, GitHub, Ubuntu VM, Rally, Heroku, Netlify,

Travis CI, Docker, Visual Studio TFS, Wrike

■ Protocols: Web APIs, SMTP, TCP/IP, HTTP, UDP, HL7 interface, Bluetooth and ZigBee

Regulatory: ITAR, MIL-STD-810F/G, MIL-STD-461, FIPS-140, former secret clearance,

US FDA Regulation 21 CFR Part 803, UL Certification, CE Registration

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MKS Instruments, Power Solutions, Rochester, NY 14623

2019-Present

- Engineering Project Manager. Manage internal, cross-function teams for the development and release of MKS RF power generators.
- Engineering Manager Embedded Software. Manage embedded software team consisting of 7 full-time engineers, 1 co-op, and 1 contractor.
 - o Instantiated software quality metrics based on Agile performance.
 - o Standardized product release notes and software configuration management process
 - Software representative for corporate SSQA Quality process
 - o Developed software process improvements to increase efficiencies of the team.
 - Track invoicing of \$1M in contractor funding
 - o Project representative for software product deliverables
- Full-Stack Web Developer. Developer for embedded product website.
 - Initial developer of the first full-stack, web-based applications for MKS Power Solutions
 - Integration of Nexus high-availability servers with Jenkins for firmware artifacts.
- <u>Product Owner.</u> Product owner for dialectic edge RF generator products lines and product web-based applications
 - Manage software development backlog priorities and release content to customers.

Agents National Title Insurance, Columbia, MO 65203

2018-2018 - Remote Position

- Full-Stack Web Developer. Developer for the new ANTIC customer website.
- Using RabbitMQ, Google Drive API, and Google Cloud App Engine, developed a Python micro service to support title insurance PDF file creation and storage.

 Developed product configuration web page, which allowed customers to set product configuration.

Thinkful, 55 Prospect St, Brooklyn, NY 11201 2017-2018

- Full-Stack Web Development Boot Camp. 5-month full-stack web development program
- Course covered all the fundamentals of full-stack web development, including React, Redux, Node, jQuery, REST APIs and databases.

United Technology Corporation/Lenel, Pittsford, New York 14534 2015-2017

- Global Product Manager. Global Product Manager for commercial security access control product. Global Product Manager for OEM product integration with enterprise access control product.
- Using Agile methodology, defined backlog and managed on-time product, API, and mobile application releases across channel segments.
- Defined 3-year product roadmap.
- Increased global product revenue by 30%
- Technically advised customers on product configurations and API integration
- Defined, configured and demonstrated product at trade shows and annual Lenel global channel partner event.
- Resolved multiple product issues including, issue with firmware download, a 7 month stop ship due to component EOL, and a backward compatibility issue on product mobile application.
- Developed and maintained product marketing collateral.
- Worked with OEM vendors to develop revenue plans.
- Cross-functionally managed product fulfillment issues during company-wide Oracle ERP migration
- Achieved UTC ACE Associate certification, equivalent to Lean Six Sigma Green Belt

Welch Allyn, Skaneateles Falls, New York 13153 2012 - 2015

- Software Project Manager. SW Project Manager for R&D new product development, supporting the Connex® Vital Sign Monitoring device and Cardio Perfect Workstation.
- Managed software development and hardware integration of the Cardio Perfect Workstation product.
- Software project manager for the integration of OEM patient movement module
- Successfully managed development and released of Connex® Vital Sign Monitoring embedded software. Release included substantial software improvements and resulted in a decline in customer complaints by 10%.
- Selected as a phase 1 participate for the Welch Allyn, Lean Six Sigma Green Belt training initiative through RIT. Green belt project improved the software development process by reducing defects by 30% and improving software development cycle time.

L-3 Communications/GCS, Victor, New York 14564 2011

- <u>Product line Manager</u>. Product Manager for the Panther VSAT (satellite terminals),
 Baseband terminals (network terminals), and Satellite Phone Service product lines.
- Developed Product Marketing Communication improvement plan.

- Established Product Plans for VSAT and Baseband product lines.
- Instituted Product Bulletins to communicate product development activities to Sales.
- Established product pricing for VSAT, Baseband and SPS product lines.
- Created competitive matrices for VSAT and Baseband product lines, including value graph of competitive features and pricing.
- Defined modification of Satellite phone service website.
- Spearheaded modifications to Government Service Administration (GSA) Schedule 70.

Harris, RF Communications, Rochester, New York 14610 2003 – 2011

- International Product Line Manager. Product Manager for the Secure Personal Radio product line (RF-7800S soldier radio with AES encryption).
- Product line return of \$38 million in revenue within 3 years of product introduction and \$48 million in FY11.
- Secured \$14 million in R&D funding for product line growth, specifically for Leader Radio development (soldier radio with integrated PDA).
- Achieved product line cost reduction of 23 percent.
- Successfully developed the \$3 million accessory product line for the Secure Personal Radio, through RFQ process.
- Cultivated strategic alliances to create additional channels for product line growth and achieved \$1 million in sales with development and execution of product plan to capture Department of Defense and Para-military markets.
- Delivered Leader Radio prototype radio under budget by \$100K.
- Outsource selection and vendor management for the Leader Radio Product development.
- Established product line pricing strategy.
- Managed new product factory introduction of vehicle and soldier radios.
- Developed product maintenance and after market strategies.
- Managed the development of embedded product firmware and software releases.
- Sourced product recommendations and system configurations for proposal submission by International Program Managers, Dealers, Sales and end-users.
- Created and maintained product line marketing material, including product requirements, product specifications, product roadmaps, data sheets, white papers, application notes, product brochures, photo shoots and product presentations in support of customer proposals, trade shows and Sales.
- Prepared and presented product line reviews to senior management and international MoD and DoD customers.
- <u>Product Line Manager</u>. Product Manager for Wireless E-mail software, Tactical Chat IP messaging software, Harris Imaging software, and Data Terminal product lines, generating over \$37 million in product revenue.
- <u>Lead Software Engineer</u>. Multi-band RF software development lead for Harris' Falcon II and Falcon III radio platforms.
- Developed requirements, designs, and implemented radio waveform controller software.

EDUCATION

Thinkful, New York, New York, 971-319-0104
Full-stack Web Development and Engineering Emersion Program

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, New York Lean Six Sigma Green Belt Certification

State University of New York, Brockport, New York

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

AFFILIATIONS/AWARDS

- Awarded patent 6204869 for Development of Control System for Test Patch Area Exposure in a Printing Machine.
- Awarded the Harris RF Communications Product and Process Innovation Award
- Member of the MKS Community Committee
- Member of the Rochester Woman's Business Network
- Former Board member of the Harris Woman's Interactive Network
- Former Volunteer Mentor for the Judicial Process Center